



CUONG VU

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Vantaa, Finland

in

Cuong is an up-and-coming Full Stack Developer who has proven his abilities in action. Cuong has already worked in an e-commerce company as well as building websites for customers. In addition to his skill set in web development, Cuong is a recent graduate with a B.B.A. degree in International Business. He has pursuits in marketing, leadership, and social entrepreneurship. This rare blend of backgrounds enables Cuong to understand the business objectives and use cases behind his work as a developer.

SKILLS

FRONTEND

JavaScript, React, Redux, D3.js, Accessibility, Material-UI, Bootstrap, TypeScript.

BACKEND

Python, Django, Flask, Node.js, Express.js, Next.js, GraphQL, REST API.

DATABASES

Firebase, MongoDB, PostgreSQL.

TESTING

Jest, React Testing Library.

DEVOPS

Bash, Docker, GitHub Actions.

CLOUD

AWS.

BASIC KNOWLEDGE

Java, Spring.

OTHER

Shopify, Solidity, Wordpress.

LANGUAGES

English - Fluent

Finnish - Novice

Vietnamese - Native

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Participated in Geebiz 2018, a global contest in leadership, cross-cultural communication, social entrepreneurship and international business

RECENT PROJECTS

GitHub User Finder

React.js, Auth0, Fusion Charts, Context API.

This project allows users to search any GitHub user profile at ease. This website includes authentication which powered by auth0. The api is provided by https://api.github.com.

E-Commerce Store

React.js, Auth0, Stripe, Context API, Netlify CLI.

Ecommerce website which utilizes Stripe for payment, and Auth0 for authentication. The main skeleton of state management is backed by Context API.

Job Search Application

React.js, JWT, MongoDB, Context API, Heroku, Node.js, Express.js.

Job search website with authentication and analysis dashboard. Users have the ability to filter searches to find jobs relevant to them.

Blog Application

React.js, JWT, MongoDB, Context API, Heroku, Node.js, Express.js.

Blog website with user authentication, and the ability to add blog posts.

Chat Application

React.js, ChatEngine.

A Simple Chat app that was constructed using ChatEngine.io.

EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Mehtaheino | Espoo, Finland | May 2022 - September 2022

- Developed an e-commerce website project for the firm using React, Node.js, and other Micro service technologies.
- Designed a scaleable web-based application structure and worked with other developers to deliver the web service on time.
- · Communicated with UI designer, sales team and content creator for efficient workflow.
- \cdot Worked with DevOps practices (Bash scripting, Docker containers, and CI/CD with GitHub Actions) and Cloud Services with AWS.

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Integrify | Helsinki, Finland | October 2021 - February 2022

- Sharpening competence as a Full Stack Developer by collaborating with other developers of different seniorities on a diverse range of projects and real-life challenges.
- · Focusing on front-end development with JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Redux in addition to other technologies and concepts such as accessibility and animations.
- · Building back-end for web-based applications with frameworks such as Node.js and Express.js.
- · Covering additional concepts such as API development and documentation, unit testing with Jest, SQL and NoSQL databases, and version control with GitHub.
- · Working with DevOps practices (Bash scripting, Docker containers, and CI/CD with GitHub Actions) and Cloud Services with AWS.

WEB DEVELOPER TRAINEE

Yield Systems Oy | Espoo, Finland | March 2021 – July 2021

- \cdot Collaborated with other team members to ideate and deliver projects on a quarterly basis.
- Worked closely with a senior developer to provide a qualified and professional UI.
- \cdot Applied industrial standard languages such as Javascript, HTML, CSS to a internal web application project.

WEB DEVELOPER INTERNSHIP

redWEB ApS | Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam | January 2020 - July 2020

- Developed an internal project for the firm using React.js, JavaScript, and other Micro frontend technologies to store learning documents and engage among each other.
- \cdot Collaborated with 10 team members including a scrum master and project owner to ideate and deliver projects on a quarterly basis.
- \cdot Contributed to the annual income of the company's revenue of \in 2.5 million euros by delivering internal projects and shadowing lead developers on large projects.

WEB DEVELOPER

Thinh Vu Phu Kien | Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam | February 2019 - August 2019

- Developed a website with WordPress for an e-commerce company consisting of five primary members focusing on the sales of smartphones and accessories leading to a monthly revenue of 135 million Vietnamese Dong (VND).

 Created several content materials for the website by bandwarking from the transfer.
- Created several content materials for the website by benchmarking from the top 10 e-commerce platforms in Asia to generate monthly sales for the company.
- · Managed paid and organic marketing on Google and Facebook using their advertising platforms on a total budget of 5 million VND.

EDUCATION

B.B.A. IN INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS

LAB University of Applied Sciences | Lappeenranta, Finland | August 2017 - December 2020